Courtney Ring Marketing Technologist

A hybrid professional with experience in roles that lie at the intersection of marketing and technology. Specialize in web solutions by bringing digital expertise to marketing, merging creativity with technology, and using data to measure success.

EXPERIENCE

Cigna Global Content Management | January 2016-Present

Web Developer - Technology Early Career Development Program (TECDP)

- Maintain the company's global websites and various microsites
- Collaborated with digital marketing to design and develop the first Corporate Responsibility report coded with Angular JS that reached 3,000 views in the first month and facilitated Investor Day hosted by the CEO
- Managed the IFP open enrollment project and created new Python scripts to process data and cut down on development time
- Supported both the design and development team to restructure and redesign the Cigna-HealthSpring's Medicare site
- Created consistency across Axure widget libraries, Digital Experience Standards, and Teamsite components that significantly improved workflow from design to development
- Used BrightEdge and Google Analytics to measure and maintain the success of content and design practices across all projects and sites

Cigna OneView | June 2015 - December 2015

User Experience Design & Development Intern

- Worked with the User Experience Design team to completely revamp Cigna's customer service application that increased usability and cut down on call times
- Helped to create a new design process by prototyping and testing usability to evaluate ease of use before implementation
- Worked on an intern project to develop a web app for caregivers that helps them with caregiving duties - Team took first place against two other intern groups

Cigna Social Media Marketing | June 2014 - August 2014

Marketing Intern

- Implemented social media strategies that created positive conversation and increased awareness of Cigna's benefits
- Developed a "Healthy Selfie" campaign and wrote copy for customer engagement that created more than 7.1 million impressions across all social media platforms
- Managed social channels during New York's "Summer Streets" event to showcase Cigna's participation in the event

EDUCATION

University of Michigan, Class of 2015

- Major in Computer Science and Communication Studies, Minor in Spanish
- Graduated with a 3.3 GPA

Study Abroad, Madrid, Spain, Winter Semester 2014

- Studied Spanish Language and Culture at IES Abroad
- Studied Communications at the local university, Universidad de Complutense

CONTACT

courtneyring@outlook.com

courtney-ring.com

in linkedin.com/in/courtneyring710

248.924.5377

AREAS OF FOCUS



Development



User Experience Design





Data & Analytics Digital Strategy

KEY SKILLS

HTML **AngularJS**

CSS Google Analytics

Python **HP** Teamsite

Javascript Photoshop

Git **AxureRP**

Bootstrap BrightEdge

SQL SASS

jQuery Chrome Devtools

For more information **CHECK OUT MY PORTFOLIO AT:**

WWW.COURTNEY-RING.COM